<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On data, programming, and technology - Open Source, Python</title><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/feeds/open-source-python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ivergara.github.io/</id><updated>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>My “Hacktober” 2018 experience</title><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/hackoctober-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ignacio Vergara Kausel</name></author><id>tag:ivergara.github.io,2018-11-06:/hackoctober-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first experience contributing during&amp;nbsp;Hacktoberfest.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My Hacktoberfest 2018 Experience
Last year I learned rather late about the Hackoctoberfest. This year, wasn’t that much different, and I didn’t manage to plan ahead on how to participate. But this story would be extremely boring if it ended like&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of the month of October, and by chance, I ended up stumbling upon a little project called deon that generates a good practices checklist for data based experiments. I’ll not go into depth about it since they do a great job at explaining what are their&amp;nbsp;objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, deon is small in scope and rather simple, but smartly done. One of their issues was to extract all the logic they had placed into the main &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; entrypoint to it own “core” function leaving the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; as a wrapper around&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this project uses click as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; framework and I’ve been using it to learn how to create and organize nice &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; applications I thought “hey, this looks like something that can be done quickly!”. And indeed it was quick, and my contribution was merged&amp;nbsp;promptly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since in my opinion the changes left the test suite a bit badly organized, I did set to change and clean up the test. Repurposing the old tests that were dealing with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; directly for the new core, and then creating lightweight &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; testing suite, focusing on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; and not on the newly extracted core. Fortunately they were using pytest which I realy like and use it exclusively by now, thus I managed to use some parametrization to reduce lines of code.
The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PR&lt;/span&gt; was merged after some minor details. Personally, I’m satisfied with the looks of the test suite, even when there is still room for&amp;nbsp;improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this success, I kept looking into the open issues. The second one I found that was more on the technical side is related to offer the creation of the checklist via a web application. Someone already had commented showing interest in implementing it, but that was more than a month earlier and there was no movement in his forked repository. Thus, I decided to start tackling it. Once again, using what I’ve been experimenting with, chose flask to implement a web application with a single endpoint. For now the basic skeleton of my suggested solution is more or less complete and further development would need feedback from the project owners/maintainers. Unfortunatelly the comment on the issue has not been considered, perhaps I should go ahead and try out a pull request&amp;nbsp;directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the end, and without forcing it, I ended contributing a tiny bit into an open source project during October-November. It does even mark my first contribution in code as previously I’ve contributed with some cleaning and docummenting of the test suite in pandas (which I hope to continue at some point). Moreover, I did contribute by using directly what what I’ve been learning since transitioning to being a full time software developer and what I’ve explored&amp;nbsp;personally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="open source"></category></entry></feed>