<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>On data, programming, and technology - Open Source, Python</title><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/feeds/open-source-python.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ivergara.github.io/</id><updated>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>My “Hacktober” 2018 experience</title><link href="https://ivergara.github.io/hackoctober-2018.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-06T10:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ignacio Vergara Kausel</name></author><id>tag:ivergara.github.io,2018-11-06:/hackoctober-2018.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first experience contributing during&amp;nbsp;Hacktoberfest.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last year I learned rather late about the hack october activity in the open source world. This year, wasn&amp;#8217;t that different, and I didn&amp;#8217;t manage to plan ahead on how to participate. But this story would be extremely boring if it ended like&amp;nbsp;this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By chance, I stumbled upon a little project called &lt;a href="https://github.com/drivendataorg/deon/"&gt;deon&lt;/a&gt; that generates a checklist of good practices for data based workflows. I&amp;#8217;ll not go into depth about it since &lt;a href="http://deon.drivendata.org/"&gt;they&lt;/a&gt; do a great job at explaining at large what their objectives&amp;nbsp;are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;deon&lt;/code&gt; is little &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; project in &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt;. And although it is rather simple, in my opinion it is smartly done. Luckily, one of their open &lt;a href="https://github.com/drivendataorg/deon/issues/66"&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; was to extract all the logic they had placed into the main &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; entrypoint command to its own &amp;#8220;core&amp;#8221; function leaving the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; as a wrapper around it. Since this project uses &lt;code&gt;click&lt;/code&gt; as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; framework and I&amp;#8217;ve been using it to learn how to create and organice nice &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; applications I thought &amp;#8220;hey, this looks like something that can be done quickly!&amp;#8221;. And indeed it was quick, and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/drivendataorg/deon/pull/73"&gt;contribution&lt;/a&gt; was merged&amp;nbsp;promptly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the changes left the test suite a bit badly organized (in my opinion), I did set to change and clean up the test suite. Repurposing the old tests that were dealing with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; directly for the new core, and then creating lightweight &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLI&lt;/span&gt; testing function. Fortunately they were using &lt;code&gt;pytest&lt;/code&gt; which I realy like and use it exclusively by now in my own work, thus I managed to use some parametrization to reduce lines of code and verbosity.
The &lt;a href="https://github.com/drivendataorg/deon/pull/74"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was recently merged to the master branch and I&amp;#8217;m satisfied with the looks of the test suite, even when there is still room for&amp;nbsp;improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this success, I kept looking into the open issues. The second one I found that was more on the technical side is related to offer the creation of checklists via a &lt;a href="https://github.com/drivendataorg/deon/issues/33"&gt;web application&lt;/a&gt;. Someone already had commented showing interest in implementing it, but that was more than a month earlier and there was no movement in his forked repository. Thus, I decided to start tackling it. Once again, using what I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with, chose &lt;code&gt;flask&lt;/code&gt; to implement a web application with a single endpoint. For now the basic skeleton of &lt;a href="https://github.com/ivergara/deon/pull/1"&gt;my suggested solution&lt;/a&gt; is more or less complete and further development would need feedback from the project&amp;nbsp;owners/maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the end, and without forcing it, I ended contributing a tiny bit into an open source project during October. It does even mark my first contribution in code as previously I&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href="https://github.com/pandas-dev/pandas/pull/21496"&gt;contributed&lt;/a&gt; with some cleaning and docummenting of the test suite in &lt;code&gt;pandas&lt;/code&gt; (which I hope to continue at some point). Moreover, I did contribute by using directly what what I&amp;#8217;ve been learning since transitioning to being a full time software&amp;nbsp;developer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="open source"></category></entry></feed>